insperity.com 2019-09-09

# Privacy policy - Insperity

## Notice of Insperity’s Privacy Policy – Effective March 4, 2011

## Related Links

Insperity’s Business Performance Solutions Privacy Policy →

### Introduction

Insperity respects your privacy. We have created this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to demonstrate our firm commitment to online privacy. This “Notice of Privacy Policy” discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for certain of Insperity’s websites, which include _Insperity.com_ and our password-protected Internet service platforms–the Employee Service CenterSM (collectively referred to as the “Insperity Web Sites”), which are available primarily to us, our clients, our employees and their families. **This Privacy Policy does not apply to all of the sites owned or operated by Insperity and you should carefully review the Privacy Policy for each site you use.** Except as noted above, this Privacy Policy applies to all information that you provide to Insperity and that Insperity maintains electronically, whether you provide the information through the Insperity Web Sites or through other means. Additionally, this Privacy Policy applies to any personal information obtained from your use (and, if applicable, your family’s use) of the Insperity Web Sites. **This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you may provide to third parties; for example, other sites linked to the Insperity websites. You should contact such third parties directly to determine their respective privacy policies.** As used herein, the terms “Insperity,” “we,” “our” and “its” when referring to Insperity, Inc. and its related companies are used only for convenience and are not intended to be an accurate description of ownership, operation or corporate/legal relationships.

* * *

### What information does Insperity collect?

If you are an employee or client of Insperity, we collect and maintain a variety of personal information about you and, if applicable, your company and employees. This information may be collected through the Employee Service Center, other Insperity websites or through paper forms submitted by you. For employees, the information we maintain includes, among other things:

  * your name, phone number and address (street and email)
  * age, marital status and occupation
  * information about your job history and employment status
  * information about your salary and benefits, including health benefits, your time off, your retirement plans, your Social Security or taxpayer identification number
  * your recruiting and training history

We may make some or all of this information available for your or your worksite employer’s use on the Employee Service Center. For clients, examples of this information include:

  * your location
  * your number of worksite employees
  * the gross payroll of worksite employees assigned to your location
  * your SIC codes
  * information about insurance and other benefit plans

Depending on the use that you make of the Insperity websites, we may also collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address (which is the unique address of your computer), information about your interests and preferences, and, if you decide to send us your resume, information included in your resume. From time to time, we may conduct surveys or offer contests or other promotional events, and gather additional personal information from you in connection with those events. Insperity may store and analyze log files from user sessions.

* * *

### What is this information used for?

We use your personal information in the course of your employment or client relationship with Insperity. Among other things, we use this information to provide you with the services available on the Employee Service Center. For example, we allow you to edit and update personal information online and allow you to download forms that have been pre-populated with your personal information. We also use your information for other things, which may include but is not limited to the following:

  * **Contacting You**  
Insperity uses your personally identifiable information to communicate with you in the course of your employment or client relationship. We may also contact you to tell you about products and services provided by Insperity’s strategic alliances and other third-party organizations. While we must be able to contact you for matters relating to your employment or your client relationship, if you do not wish to receive e-mail communications from Insperity regarding strategic alliance offers or other third-party products and services, you may opt out of receiving such communications by following the procedure set forth in such email.  Insperity will continue to contact you for matters relating to your employment or your client relationship.
  * **Use of IP Address**  
IP addresses are numbers that are automatically assigned to your computer, and if associated with other individually identifiable information, could be considered personal information. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer and improve the Insperity Web Sites. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information, some of which we aggregate and then share with our strategic alliances or potential strategic alliance companies. We also use your IP address to keep track of the information you have seen on our sites.
  * **Use of Cookies**  
Cookies are a standard technology used by commercial Web services to store small pieces of information on your hard drive by sending a small string of text to your browser. They make your use of the Insperity Web Sites more pleasing and efficient by, for example, “personalizing” your user interface or identifying which parts of a site you have previously visited. They also enable us to pre-populate, or automatically fill out, forms and schedules. They enable us to tailor the information you receive and to assist third-party organizations with whom we have strategic alliances by identifying you as an Insperity client, employee or user of the Insperity Web Sites. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, unless you have configured yours not to accept them. In order for us to provide you with services on the Employee Service Center, your browser must accept cookies, as they are essential for site administration and security. Insperity does not use cookies either to collect individually identifiable information or to collect non-individually identifiable information using a cookie that is combined with a personal identifier.
  * **Other General Information**  
If you send us your resume, we use that information to assist you with job placement. Insperity may also collect the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (e.g., aol.com); the date and time you access the Insperity websites, the Internet address of any Web site from which you link directly to the Insperity Web Sites as well as collecting and storing other information in a user’s log file. A user’s log file tells Insperity where a user comes from when entering the Insperity Web Sites, which part of the Insperity Web Sites the user visits as well as where the user goes when leaving the Insperity Web Sites; and how much time the user spends in the Insperity websites. In addition, Insperity may collect email addresses and other personal information from persons who are not current employees or clients of Insperity.
  * **Rewarding Use of the Insperity Web Sites**  
Insperity may use information it collects in order to reward or provide incentives to employees, client companies or other users of the Insperity websites for visiting the Insperity websites, using services provided on the Insperity websites, or for visiting the websites of Insperity’s strategic alliances or affiliates.

* * *

### With whom is this information shared?

Insperity shares personal information only as described below:

  * **Other Insperity Companies and Third-Party Contractors**  
We may share your information among related companies of Insperity, even if the related company is not a party to your client service or employment agreement. In addition, we may from time to time transfer our database of employee information to third-party contractors who analyze such information on behalf of Insperity for the purpose of, among other things, targeting e-mails to employees regarding strategic alliance offers, or who mail marketing materials to employees regarding strategic alliance offers. Additionally, we may from time to time transfer our database of employee information to a third-party contractor to whom we have outsourced certain of the services that Insperity provides to its clients and/or employees. For example, Insperity may outsource its employment verification services to a third-party vendor who performs such services on behalf of Insperity. Such third-party contractors are contractually bound to hold all such information in confidence and not to share such information with any parties other than Insperity.
  * **Your Worksite Employer**  
If you are an employee, most of your personal information is also available to your individual worksite employer. However, Insperity does not provide information regarding your physical and/or mental health to any third party for any purposes, unless compelled by a governmental or legal authority.
  * **Governmental Authorities, Compliance with Law and Protection of  
Insperity and Others**  
We provide information to governmental authorities when required to do so by law (for example, we report information regarding your compensation and withholding to the U.S. Internal Revenue Service and state taxing authorities). Insperity will also provide personally identifiable information to third parties if compelled to do so by an appropriately empowered governmental or legal authority, or, as necessary, to protect Insperity’s rights or the rights of third parties.
  * **Benefit Plan Providers**  
Insperity will also provide personally identifiable information to its third-party benefit providers in conjunction with the administration of its benefit plans.
  * **Medical Emergencies**  
If necessary to respond to an apparent medical emergency, Insperity may disclose selected employee information.
  * **Strategic Alliances**  
Insperity has entered into marketing agreements, strategic alliances and other relationships with third-party organizations that may offer or provide products and services to you, sometimes under discounted or preferential terms. We may provide certain information including, but not limited to, your email address and other contact information to our strategic alliance and other third-party organizations so that they may contact you directly regarding products and services that may be of particular interest to you and/or your company. These strategic alliance and third-party organizations are contractually bound to hold your email address and other contact information in confidence and not to share your information with parties other than Insperity.  We also sometimes agree to give these third parties (including potential parties to strategic alliances) aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about our clients, employees or visitors. Please directly contact any strategic alliances or third parties for instructions on how you may opt out of receiving marketing communications from such strategic alliances or other third-party organizations.
  * **Business Transfers**  
As Insperity continues to develop its businesses, it may sell various aspects of its business. If Insperity sells a portion of its business, it will transfer personal information associated with that business as part of such a sale. Also, in the unlikely event that Insperity or substantially all of its assets are acquired, personal information regarding employees and clients will be one of the transferred assets.

* * *

### What access do you have to information you provide?

You have access to much of your personal information through the Employee Service Center, where you can view and update most of the personal information we maintain.

* * *

### Security measures

Insperity makes access to your personally identifiable information subject to certain security measures, including technological controls such as “firewalls,” in accordance with industry standards. When the use of the Insperity websites involve the transmission of confidential information about you or Insperity, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to establish a secure connection between your PC and our server. SSL allows the transmission of encrypted information from your PC to our server and back again and is the industry standard for Internet platform security. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so while Insperity strives to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to Insperity.

* * *

### Disclaimer of responsibility for privacy policy and content at linked sites

The Insperity websites may provide you with links to other websites. We are not responsible for those sites and cannot control the use of information that you submit once you reach those sites, nor can we control the content of what is offered on those sites or on links from those sites. You should contact such third-party websites directly to determine their privacy policies.

* * *

### Use of information from third parties

We may use information about you provided to us by third parties (such as credit reporting agencies or strategic alliances) in order to offer you their services and products, to improve our own services or to evaluate your eligibility for our services.

* * *

### This is not a children’s website

Insperity does not knowingly solicit data from children, and we do not knowingly market to children.

* * *

### Applicable only to U.S. residents

The Insperity websites are designed for and intended only for the use of clients located in the United States and employees who are U.S. citizens or are residents of the United States. If you are a client that is located outside of the United States, you are not authorized to access any of the Insperity websites.

* * *

### Changes in these policies and practices

Insperity reserves the right to change its privacy policies and practices periodically, without providing individual notice, by updating this Privacy Policy notice. This Privacy Policy was last updated on March 4, 2011. You agree that it is your responsibility to monitor such updates. Your continued use of any of the Insperity websites after such revisions have been made or your failure to object in writing to any notice of such change will constitute your full acceptance of such revised Privacy Policy.

* * *

### California Residents – Your Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year.  If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to the address provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.  Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the Section 1798.83 requirements, and only information on covered sharing for California customers will be included in our response.

* * *

### More information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please write to:

Insperity  
Linda Jones  
Attn: WebSupport (Privacy Policy Inquiry)  
Mail Code 1-3240  
19001 Crescent Springs Drive  
Kingwood, Texas 77339-3802

Fax: 800-878-6813  
Telephone: 877-804-8978  
Email address: [csr.assistant@insperity.com  
](mailto:csr.assistant@insperity.com)

In accordance with California Civil Code § 1786.20, the representative named above will be able to assist you with additional information regarding our privacy practices or policies in the event of a compromise of your information.

This site uses cookies to store information on your computer. Some are essential to make our site work; others help us improve the user experience. By using the site, you consent to the placement of these cookies. Read our privacy policy to learn more.
